[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle：所以我现在要开始一个练习
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So I'm now going to open an exercise
这边有四个固定版本
four fixed version on this side and
我要开始练习6。
I'm going to open up exercise 6.
再一次，向你展示处理EX6的并排方式。
And again, show you the side by side way of dealing with ex6.
因此，我们仍然有与EX5相同的get文件。
So, we still have our same get file the way we did with ex5.
但我们如何处理这个地图减少的事情。
But how are we going to handle this map reduce thing.
好吧，我将从“file1”列表开始，
Well, I'm gonna start with a list of "file1",
“二号文件”，“三号文件”，好吗？
"file two", "file three", okay?
现在我仍然要做一个.map调用和调用.map，这是数组映射。
Now I'm still going to do a .map call and call .map, this is the array map.
普通的普通数组传递给getFile。
Plain old normal array pass it getFile.
最后，我现在有了一个序列数组。
And the end of that I now have an array of sequences.
是不是每个人都意识到这不再是一系列的承诺了。
Does everybody catch that it's not an array of Promises anymore.
它是异步序列的数组。
It's an array of async sequences.
我想把这些序列
And I want to turn those sequences
变成我可以链接成序列的东西。
into something that I can chain into a sequence.
所以我可以在这里做一个.Reduce呼叫
So I could do a .reduce call here and
采用完全相同的方法用.seq和.val链接东西。
take the exact same approach of chaining things in with .seq and .val.
所以我可以做和我在前4所做的完全一样的事情
So I could do exactly the same thing I did in EX-4 and
它的工作方式将完全相同。
it would work exactly the same way.
但是有一个更简单的方法通过认识到一个事实
But there's an even easier way of doing it by recognizing the fact that one of
如果你愿意的话，诺言图书馆的美德再一次给你一些额外的糖。
the virtues again of a Promise library giving you some extra sugar if you will.
其中的一种糖是，异步方法至少有一些方法。
One of the sugars is that the asynquence methods at least some of the methods.
许多方法将接收多个项目
Many of the methods will receive multiple items
好像你给那东西打了好几次电话。
as if you called the thing multiple times.
因此，使用.seq，我可以将多个序列传递到其中
So with .seq I can pass multiple sequences into it and
我不必为每个序列调用一次seq。
I don't have to call seq once for each sequence.
我可以向它传递多个序列。
I can pass multiple sequences into it.
所以如果我这里有这组序列。
So if I have this set of sequences here.
我可以直接将它们传递到.seq调用中。
I could just pass them directly into a .seq call.
不幸的是，事情没那么简单，因为seq不加薪，
Now unfortunately, it's not as simple as that, because seq doesn't take a raise,
因为无法知道您是否希望该数组为值或
cuz there's no way to know whether or not you want that array to be a value or
是否希望它是序列数组。
whether you want it to be an array of sequences.
所以在这个意义上它不是多态的，但是
So it's not polymorphic in that sense but
有了ES6，我们所需要的就是在阵列中展开的点。
with the ES6 all we need is the dot dot dot to spread out in array.
所以我们要展开一系列的序列。
So we are spreading out an array of sequences.
&GT；&GT；Kyle：但这里还有最后一个小细节，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: But there's one last little detail here,
那就是我们还没有对这些输出进行排序，是吗？
which is we're not sequencing in those outputs yet are we?
因此我们可以通过识别将输出排序为这些单独的序列
So we could sequence in the outputs into these individual sequences by recognizing
另一个转变需要发生，因为我需要每个
that another transformation needs to occur as I need to take each
单步序列并将其转换为两步序列。
single step sequence and turn it into a two step sequence.
等待事件、等待文本并打印的顺序。
A sequence of waiting for the event, waiting for the text and printing it.
所以我要做另一个.map调用，不是为了减少，而是
So I'm gonna do another .map call, not to reduce but
另一个.map调用需要一个序列。
another .map call which takes a sequence.
为了简短和清晰，我将其命名为SQ。
I'll call it sq just for shortness and clarity.
它需要一个序列并需要对其进行转换，对吗？
It takes a sequence and needs to do a transformation on it, right?
我们的转变是什么？
What's our transformation?
&GT；&GT；Kyle：这将是一个转变。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: That would be a transformation.
这将把序列推入更大序列
That will push that sequence into the bigger sequence and
把它推到更大的序列中，把它推到更大的序列中。
push it into the bigger sequence and push it into the bigger sequence.
为了进一步明确我们
To make that further clear we're
在这里将这些作为一组函数传递并不是严格必要的，但是
going to pass these as a set of functions in this isn't strictly necessary but
现在这是一组被推入seq的函数，所以
now this is a set of functions being pushed into the seq so
他们会在适当的时间被召唤，好吗？
that they will be called at the appropriate time, okay?
所以他们应该在没有函数包装器的情况下工作，只是为了
So this would they should work without the function wrapper here but just to make
很明显，我们可以将其转换为生成序列的函数组。
it clear we can turn this into a array of functions that produce a sequence.
这就是sequence传统上所期望的。
That's what sequenced traditionally expects.
或者我们可以简单地将其转换为序列数组。
Or we can just simply turn it into an array of sequences.
&gt；&gt；kyle：实际上，如果，让我后退，会发生什么。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: And what's gonna happen if, actually, so let me back up.
如果我们把它变成一组独立的序列会发生什么
So what's gonna happen if we turn this into an array of independent sequences
我们可能会在file1之前打印file2，因为
is that we might get file2 printed before file1 because
这些仍然是独立的序列。
these are still independent sequences.
我们使它们依赖的方式是按照函数包装器和
The way we make them dependent is to defer with the function wrappers and
这就是这次活动的目的，好吗？
that was the purpose for the function, okay?
我们已经将字符串数组转换为序列数组
We've turned an array of strings into an array of sequences and
然后我们将序列数组转换为
then we turn an array of sequences into an array of
将返回这些序列的函数。
functions that will return those sequences.
&gt；&gt；演讲者2：我的问题是我们不能用同样的
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: My question is can we not implement that previous one with the same
在打印输出时映射并延迟它。
map and defer it when we print the output.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：承诺的问题，这种技术不起作用的原因
&gt;&gt; Kyle: The problem with Promises, the reason why that technique doesn't work
在这里承诺，是他们不能接受多种功能。
over here with Promises, is that they can't accept multiple functions.
Asynquence可以接受多个函数，它知道如何处理它。
Asynquence can accept multiple functions and it knows what to do with it.
但在这里你不能这样做，所以你实际上必须手动链接它们
But you can't do that over here, so you actually have to manually chain them
这就是为什么我们需要减少呼叫。
together which is why we need to the reduce call.
减少可能对你的大脑有更好的效果，如果是这样，那很好，
Reduce may work better for your brain and if so that's great,
你可以用异步的方式做到这一点。
you can do that with asynquence.
但我只是想告诉你我们可以摆脱复杂性
But I'm just trying to show you that we can get rid of the complexity
减少和简单地做两个map调用。
of reduce and simply do two map calls.
利用这一事实，我们可以访问接收函数组。
Taking advantage of the fact that we can access receive an array of functions.
我失去了所有人吗？
Did I lose everybody?
我能不能竖起大拇指，如果它至少有一半的意义，好吧，对吧。
Can I get a thumbs up if it's making at least half sense, okay, right.
我知道这里有点复杂。
I get that there's a little bit of complexity here.
我呈现给你的任何东西都不应该像你立即成为它的大师一样。
Nothing that I'm presenting to you should be like immediately you're a master on it.
这都是给你的东西，它给你灵感去挖掘和
This is all presenting you stuff that it's giving you the inspiration to go dig and
学习并实践这些东西。
learn these things and practice them.
没有什么可以替代
There's no substitute for
练习到东西舒服的地步，好吗？
the practice to get to the point where the stuff is comfortable, okay?
&gt；&gt；Kyle：好的，这是练习五和
&gt;&gt; Kyle: All right, so that's exercise five and
我们下一个讨论的话题。
six our next topic of discussion.
我要说的最后一点。
My last point to make.
如果你想了解更多关于异步的知识，甚至比文档更多，我写道
If you want to know more about asynquence, more than even the documentation, I wrote
关于它的两三部分的博客系列，你可以阅读更多关于异步和
two or three part blog series on it and you can read more about asynquence and
它的设计原则和考虑使用它的方式。
its design principles and ways to think about using it.
所以，如果你有兴趣了解更多，请随意。
So if you're interested in learning more be my guest.
请随意阅读它们。
Feel free to read about them.
在休息期间，有几个问题让我觉得我可能会
Over the break, there were several questions where it felt like I might have
在我们关于EX6，练习6的讨论结束时，造成了一点混乱。
created a little bit of confusion at the end of our discussion on ex6, exercise 6.
所以我想回到这一点，并确保我有一点清楚。
So I wanted to circle back to that and make sure I was a little bit clear.
这样，我们就不会把困惑留在周围。
That way, we didn't leave the confusion around it.
首先，让我说，我们将要讨论的一切都是真的
At the outset, let me say that everything that we're about to discuss is really
更多的是关于JavaScript的，更少的是关于异步的。
more about JavaScript and much less about asynquence.
所以这不是关于异步的一些复杂性。
So this isn't some complexity about asynquence.
它只是了解JavaScript中发生的机制。
It's just understanding the mechanisms that are are happening in JavaScript.
但我所做的是我已经勾勒出了我们最初谈论的内容，
But what I've done is I've sketched out what we were originally talking about,
就在右边，你可以看到我直接回来了
which was over here on the right, you can see that I'm returning directly
带有val输出的序列放在上面。
the sequence with the val output put onto it.
所以当你在想象或者理解上有困难的时候
So any time you're having trouble picturing or understanding or
弄清楚什么是地图或地图，减少或它正在做的任何事情。
sussing out what a map or map and reduce or whatever it is doing.
我鼓励你在头脑中展开它，至少展开几个
I encourage you to unroll that in your mind at least unroll a few
你脑海中的每一步甚至都是这样打出来的
steps of it in your mind even type it out that way you have
更清楚地了解正在发生的事情。
a clearer picture of what's happening.
[咳嗽]所以我所做的就是在左边做这件事。
[COUGH] So what I've done is do that over here on the left.
我已经展示了右边正在发生的事情，当我们直接
I've unrolled what was happening over there on the right when we directly
返回序列和val输出。
returned the sequence and val output.
您注意到，我从一个字符串数组开始。
You notice that I start out with an array of strings.
这个map调用将其更改为序列数组。
This map call changes it into an array of sequences.
这个map调用将其更改为其他序列的数组。
This map call changes it into an array of other sequences.
具有.val和输出的序列，但
Sequences which have .val and output but
仍然有三个独立的序列，这意味着它们
there are still three independent sequences, which means they're
能够独立进行，独立不是我们想要的。
going to be able to independently proceed and independence is not what we want here.
我们试图在它们之间建立依赖性，以便它们正确排序。
We're trying to create dependence between them so that they sequence correctly.
所以如果我们想象左边这里发生的事情，
So if we visualize what's happening over here on the left,
你可以看到它就像在三个独立的序列中传递。
you can see that on it's like passing in three independent sequences.
所以每一个都能在它完成后立即进入它的输出，
So each one of those is able to go to its output as soon as it finishes,
也就是说我们不协调
which means we're not coordinating
S1输出发生在S2输出之前，S3输出之前。
the s1 output to happen before the s2 output before the s3 output.
这实际上是所有的JavaScript，与异步没有任何关系。
That's really all JavaScript, that's got nothing to do with asynquence.
只是这三样东西现在是独立的。
It's just that these things these three things are independent right now.
我们希望他们能够依赖。
And we want them to be dependent.
也要指出这个点，点。
Also to point out this dot, dot, dot.
它发生在我们产生了一个数组之后，所以我继续
Its happening after we've produced an array so I went ahead and
在这里放入包装圆括号，以清楚地显示出那个圆点
put in the wrapping parentheses here to make it clear that dot dot dot
这里使用的是展开阵列。
being used here is spreading out an array.
所以我们从一个数组开始
So we started out with an array and
我们把它作为一系列实际的论点展开。
we spread it out as a series of actual arguments.
如果.seq方法采用数组。
If the .seq method took an array.
那么我们在这里所做的一切都将是完全相同的，除了我们会
Then everything that we did over here would be exactly the same except we'd take
走出.。
out the...
Sequence不采用数组，因为无法了解多态
Sequence doesn't take an array because there's no way polymorphically to know
无论您是否打算将其作为传递的单一值或
whether or not you intend that to be a single value passed through or
是否希望它是要解释的值的数组。
whether you intend it to be an array of values to be interpreted.
所以正因为如此，我之前说过，
So because of that I said earlier,
我不喜欢多态，我不喜欢混淆传统的多态。
I don't like polymorphism I don't like confusing conventional polymorphism.
所以它不是多态的。
So it's just not polymorphic in that way.
这意味着你不能传递一个数组。
Meaning you can't pass on an array.
你必须把它们分开传递。
You have to pass them in separately.
正如您将在解决方案文件中看到的那样，老式的方法可以使用该方法。
The old school way as you'll see in the solution files to use that apply.
我试图帮助你理解ES6是如何让这些事情变得清晰的。
I'm trying to help you understand how ES6 helps makes these things clear.
所以这是一个展开的阵列，现在应该很清楚了，
So that's a spreading out an array and it should be clear now that,
这就是为什么这是不够，因为这是三个独立的序列
that's why this is not sufficient, cuz these are three independent sequences
这将独立输出，这不是我们想要的。
that will output independently, and that's not what we want.
所以如果我们回到我们结束的地方，
So if we go back to where we did end up,
也就是说，我们返回的是一个返回这些序列的函数。
which is that we're returning a function that returns those sequences.
那就相当于我们展开它时所发生的事情
Then the equivalent of what's happening when we unroll it
传入了三个独立的函数。
is that there are three independent functions being passed in.
所以我们所做的是从一个字符串数组开始产生一个
So what we've done is start with an array of strings produce an array of
序列，现在我们将其映射到函数组。
sequences and now we're mapping that to an array of functions.
然后我们当然把函数组作为单独的点展开
And then we of course dot dot dot spread out the array of functions as individual
函数参数。
function arguments.
这里有一个函数，这里有一个函数。
So I have a function here, a function here, and a function here.
现在我们确实需要了解一些关于异步如何工作的具体内容。
Now we do need to understand something specific about how asynquence works.
这不应该令人困惑，但这是我们应该特别指出的事情。
It shouldn't be confusing but it's something we should call out specifically.
这就是说，大多数接受一个或多个函数的方法。
And that is that most of the methods that take one or more functions.
如果你传递两个或三个函数，就像我们在这里传递三个函数一样。
If you pass two or three functions like we're passing three functions here.
API将运行第一个函数，并且
The API will run the first function and
然后，只有在第一个函数完成后才继续执行第二个函数，依此类推。
then go on to the second function only after the first one finished and so forth.
所以每件事都是连续的。
So does everything serially.
所以这三个函数即使它们被传递到相同的
So these three functions even though they're being passed into the same
Sequence方法仍将完全运行此方法，
sequence method are still going to run this one entirely to its completion,
这意味着等待该序列完成。
which means wait for that sequence to finish.
然后，运行此函数并完全运行该序列。
And then, run this function and run that sequence entirely to completion.
然后，这个功能和那个序列完全完成。
And then, this function and that sequence entirely to completion.
所以这就是展开我们在右手边生产的东西的方式，
So that is the way to unroll what we've produced over here on the right-hand side,
我们已经创建了一个函数列表
is that we've created a list of functions and
将这些函数扩展到序列调用。
spread those functions out to the sequence call.
而这个，如果将多个函数传递到.seq中会让人感到困惑，
And this, if that's confusing passing multiple functions into .seq,
您也可以将其可视化为三个单独的.seq调用。
you can also alternatively visualize that as three separate .seq calls.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：希望这能让它更清晰。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So hopefully that makes it clearer.
但其中的每一个都将依次发生，连续发生。
But each one of those is going to happen in sequence, serially.
希望，这消除了一些我们可能已经造成的混乱
Hopefully, that cleared up some of the confusion that we might have wrought by
尝试快速通过解决方案的一次性部分
trying to go through quickly the throwaway parts of the solution for
练习六，它让我们更清楚为什么会在这里结束。
exercise six, and it makes it more clear why we ended up over here.
再一次只是克制。
And again just to refrain.
其中绝大多数是使用JavaScript机制的理解。
The vast majority of that is understanding using JavaScript mechanisms.
它与异步本身几乎没有关系。
It has very, very little to do with asynquence itself.
唯一特定于异步的部分是它期望个体的值和
The only part that's asynquence specific is that it expects individual values and
它将连续执行这些操作。
it will do them serially.